# **Stephan Santos**

SEATTLE. WA

#### CONTACT

https://www.stephansantos.com stephan.pssantos@gmail.com (206) 307-4338

**SUMMARY:** Software engineer with ~4 years of professional development work. Successfully delivered multiple individual and team projects, participating in every stage of the software development lifecycle from conception through to long-term end user support.

## **SKILL SET**

**LANGUAGES** 

C#, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS

#### **TOOLS & FRAMEWORKS**

Node.js, .NET, PowerShell, Git, Docker, React, Blazor, OpenAPI, Postman, Adobe Creative Suite

### **SERVICES**

Azure DevOps, Azure Cloud Services, Dynamics CRM, MS Power Platform, SharePoint

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

KING COUNTY PROSECUTING ATTORNEY'S OFFICE IT DEPARTMENT (SEATTLE, WA)

- Developed and maintained line of business applications for company of 700+ users.
- Prepared data analytics dashboards via Power BI and over 100 automated reports via SSRS to help facilitate data-driven decision-making within the company.
- Technical point of contact for SaaS/COTS vendors, coordinating integration and deployment, organizing training and communications, and preparing internal troubleshooting and end user documentation.

Journey Applications Developer ...... Oct 2019 – Jul 2021

- Developed multiple Dynamics 365 applications as part of a suite of business applications used by a third of staff members that allowed the company to drop certain legacy applications, achieve a 90% reduction in local network storage costs, and ease work from home transitions.
- Promoted to Senior after delivery of complete application suite.

Web Developer ...... Jul 2018 – Oct 2019

- Project lead for a React web application hosted on Azure used regularly by over 2,000 local government employees to register new legal documents, reducing administrative time from days to minutes. Integrates with existing B2C login gateways and programmatically connected to company's SharePoint storage.
- Provided new features, content, and support for SiteCore CMS, SharePoint, Teams, and the company's legacy MS office applications (Excel and Word VB scripts, Access databases.)
- Led transition from local network storage to OneDrive for individual user file storage.

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE DEVELOPER ASSOCIATE - Achieved February 2022 COMPTIA A+ - Achieved July 2019

SELF STUDY of C#, .NET MAUI/Xamarin, Blazor, Docker, Azure, and NoSQL DBs - 2022-ongoing

ATENEO DE MANILA UNIVERSITY (QUEZON CITY, PHILIPPINES) - 2010-2014

- Graduated with a bachelor's degree in information design.
- Key Coursework: Web Development, Visual Communication, User Experience, Wireframing